<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A view of all the right honourable the Lord Mayors of this honorable citty of London With the personages, and also such chiefe occasions as happened in euery seuerall mayors time, as also their charitable gifts are set downe, and the places of their burials. Beginning at the first yeare of her maiesties happy raigne, and continued vnto this present yeare 1601. by W.I. of London printer.</title>
            <author>Jaggard, William, 1569-1623.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1599</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 51 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 48 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A04223</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 14343</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S109094</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99844744</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99844744</idno>
            <idno type="VID">9584</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A04223)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 9584)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1277:03)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A view of all the right honourable the Lord Mayors of this honorable citty of London With the personages, and also such chiefe occasions as happened in euery seuerall mayors time, as also their charitable gifts are set downe, and the places of their burials. Beginning at the first yeare of her maiesties happy raigne, and continued vnto this present yeare 1601. by W.I. of London printer.</title>
                  <author>Jaggard, William, 1569-1623.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[47] leaves : ports. (woodcuts)  </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[By William Jaggard?] for William Iaggard and Thomas Pauyer and are to be sold at his house in Cornhill, at the signe of the Cat and two Parats,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Printed at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1601.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Dedication signed: William Iaggard.</note>
                  <note>The first four words of title and the imprint date are xylographic.</note>
                  <note>Printer's name conjectured by STC (addendum).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>London (England) --  Officials and employees --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>Lauren Proux</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>Lauren Proux</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:1"/>
            <p>A view of all THE RIGHT HO<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>nourable the Lord Mayors of this <hi>Honorable Citty of London.</hi> With the perſonages, and alſo ſuch chiefe occaſions as happened in eue<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>y ſeuerall mayors time, as alſo their charitable gifts are ſet downe, and the places of their burials.</p>
            <p>Beginning at the firſt yeare of her maieſties happy raigne, and continued vnto this preſent yeare 1601. by W. I. of London Printer.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Printed at London for</hi> William Iaggard and Thomas Pauyer and are to be ſold at his houſe in Cornhill, at the ſigne of the Cat and two Parats. 1601.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="dedication">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:2"/>
            <head>TO THE RIGHT HO<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>norable Sir William Ryder Lord Mayor of this Honourable <hi>Citty of London.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">R</seg>Ight Honourable, I find in common experience that euery Author fitteth the patronage of his long labour, vnto ſome perſonage of eſteeme: and in knitting vp his reſolution, preſumeth vpon the fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uour of ſuch a one, as in his long debated conceit, best vnderſtan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deth the ſubiect whereon hee laboureth: Euen ſo I, being h at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tened forth by other mens good haps, haue only made choiſe of your honour, vnder whoſe fauour I hope to be protected: and finding it my duty (conſidring the honor it hath pleaſed God to beſtow vpon you) to reſt my labor vppon ſo worthy a rocke. The cauſes mouing me to this worke might be many, but eſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pecially foure. Firſt, the examples of good iuſtice done by your predeceſſors. Secondly, the chriſtian and charitable patterns left for after ages, by their exam<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ples. Thirdly, how many poore in this citty and elſe-where are relieued to the worlds end, by their liberalities and godly prouiſions. And fourthly but princi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pally (Right Honorable that which no good ſubiect will obiect againſt) the great mercy of God, in bleſſing this little land with ſo precious a Prince, in whoſe raigne may be told to after ages, that neuer any one age heard before, that 43. Lord Mayors of this Citty, haue ſeene 43. yeares all in peace, vnder ſo gracious a Soueraigne: In peace one yea<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>e to take place, and in that great bleſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing (Peace) the next yeare to reſign againe (God long preſerue that root from whence ſuch bloſſomes ſpring.) I had thought to haue put it out naked, but be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing better aduiſed, I haue in duty (being a poore Citizen) preſented your Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor with the firſt fruit of my labour, praying pardon at your kind hands for my raſh and rude preſumption vpon your patience, if I ſhal any way offend. I haue in this collection dealt as faithfully towardes euery particular perſonage, as I find recorded, and (I truſt) giuen no cauſe of offence to any good knight, either liuing or deceaſed. Thus finiſhing my taske in your yeare of gouernement, I ſhall daily pray to God for your Honours good ſucceſſe.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Your Honors in all duty, William Iaggard.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:3"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:3"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 1. Sir Thomas Lee <hi>Mercer.</hi> 1558</p>
            <p>THis ſir Thomas Lee (or Leigh) gouerned this worthy Citty of London, in the yeare 1558. He was not long in this authoritye, but God ſent vs our gracious and Noble queene Elizabeth to raigne and gouerne ouer this happy land. At the ſolemnization of her Maieſties Coronation, it pleaſed hir highneſſe to make this lord Mayor Butler for that high feaſt, &amp; gaue vnto him a cup of golde for his dilligent paines and diſcharge of his high office. Alſo in this yeare the cittizens of London had a muſter before the queene at Greene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wich of 1400. men, all furniſhed and ſet forth by the ſeuerall companies of the citty of London. Sir Thomas Lee lies buried in the Mercers chappell.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Iohn Hlaſe.</item>
                     <item>Richard Champion.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:4"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:4"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 2 Sir Wil. Huet <hi>Clothworker.</hi> 1559</p>
            <p>SIr William Huet was next that had the gouernment and was lord Mayor of this famous Citty. He was the firſt mayor of the Worſhipfull Company of the Clothworkers, he was very charitable and a very good commonwealth man. In this yeare on michealmaſſe eeuen was publiſhed a proclamation con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning baſe coine, (called the third fall of baſe money, and for it came newe coine of fine ſiluer. He hauing but one daughter, married with maiſt. Edward Osborne (being his man) and after Lord mayor of this citty, who erected in re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>membrance of his ſaid mayſter &amp; father, a pretty monument, in the church of ſaint martin Orgar, where he was buried the 25. of Ianuary 1566.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Thomas Lodge.</item>
                     <item>Roger martin.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:5"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:5"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 3. Sir Wil. Cheſter <hi>Draper.</hi> 1560</p>
            <p>IN this yeare 1560. Sir William Cheſter was elected &amp; choſen Lord Mayor of this Citty, no matter worthy note haopened throughout this yeare, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning this Citty, ſaue only about the moneth of April, there was one whip<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ped for taking vpon him a falſe Chriſt, and after his puniſhment confeſſed that Chriſt was in heauen. This yeare vpon the fourth of Iune betweene the houres of foure and fiue after noone, Paules ſteeple was ſet on fire by lightning, ſo ter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rible, that in foure houres, the ſteeple with the roofes of the church were conſu<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>med. This knight liued after this place of honor ſome yeares, and lies buried in ſaint Edmunds church in Lumbard ſtreet.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Chriſtopher Draper.</item>
                     <item>Thomas Rowe.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:6"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:6"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 4. Sir Wil. Harper <hi>Merchantaylor.</hi> 1561</p>
            <p>SIr William Harper Lord Mayor of this citty of London, ſhewed many good workes of chriſtianity, amongſt many vertues, he erected a free ſchoole in the auncient towne of Bedford, (in which towne he was borne. This yeare her Maieſty by proclamation reſtored vnto all her louing ſubiectes diuers ſmall pieces of money, from ſix pence to three farthinges. Alſo this yeare was made ready and ſet forward her Maieſties forces for the recouery of the town of New hauen, which was by Gods aſſiſtance effected and got by the Engliſh. Manye excellent deedes of charity proceeded from this good knight, which are not yet gathered, he was buried in Lumbard ſtreet, at ſaint Mary Wolnoth.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Alexander Avenon.</item>
                     <item>Humfrey Baskervile</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:7"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:7"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 5 Sir Thomas Lodge <hi>Grocer.</hi> 1562</p>
            <p>THis yeare ſir Thomas Lodge was Lord Mayor, in whoſe yeare the Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſh men returned from Newhauen, at the comming home of which com<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>panies, there aroſe a great plague, eſpecially within this citty, and as M. Stow recordeth, there died of all diſeaſes within this citty the liberties &amp; out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pariſhes 23660. Of the plague, 20136. By reaſon hereof no tearme was kept at Michaelmaſſe. Alſo there was a great Earthquake in England, and a great tempeſt about London, whereby much hurt happened about Charing-croſſe. This Knight hath no other matters recorded of his time, what deedes hee did in this citty or in his company, as yet I find not. He lies in Aldermary church.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>William Allin.</item>
                     <item>Richard Champion.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:8"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:8"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 6 Sir Iohn White <hi>Grocer.</hi> 1563</p>
            <p>IN this yeare 1563. was ſir Iohn White Lord Mayor of this Honourable citty but by reaſon the peſtilence was not yet cleare, he was forced to leaue the ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuſtomed maner of taking his Oath at Weſtminſter, and receiued it at the vt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moſt gate of the Tower of London, neither was there any feaſt at the Guildhal. Hyllary tearme was kept in Hartford Caſtle. The Armorers through ſute made to this Lord Mayor, got a Watch graunted vpon ſaint Peters eeven. It was alſo enacted by a common councell, that if any Citizen were forced to ſell his hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhold ſtuffe, he ſhould haue it cryed by a Belman, and then ſold by a common out cryer appointed for that purpoſe. He was not buried in London.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Edward Bankes.</item>
                     <item>Rowland Heyward.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:9"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:9"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 7. Sir Richard Mallary <hi>Mercer.</hi> 1564</p>
            <p>SIr Richard Mallary was according to auncient cuſtome by the common con<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſent of this citty elected and choſen Lord Mayor for this yeare, in whoſe time I finde little recorded. In this yeare was the great Froſt, being very ſharpe &amp; extreame, and continued many daies, inſomuch as the Thames was ſo frozen vp. that from London bridge to Weſtminſter, diuers courtyers ſhot at prickes vppon the yce. It continued till the third of Ianuary, and then came ſo ſwift a thaw, that within two daies the yce was ſo cleane conſumed, as if no ſuch froſt had hapned, but in the farewel thereof it bare downe Owſe bridge, and did much hurt. The Watch was this yeare continued on ſaint Peters eeuen, Nothing can I ſay further of this knight as yet, He lies buryed in the Mercers chappell.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Edward Iackman.</item>
                     <item>Lyonell Ducket.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:10"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:10"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 8. Sir Rich. Champion <hi>Draper.</hi> 1565</p>
            <p>THis yeare ſir Richard Champion was Lord Mayor of London, who ſhewed himſelfe very dilligent and carefull in the diſcharge of the truſt to him com<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>mitted, He liued but a ſhort time after this his high office, ſome three years <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>t his death he left a very chriſtian and charitable token of remembrance to all af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter ages, for as in his life time he relieued the poore, ſo he hath ordained a week<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly ſtipend to be beſtowed vpon the poore of the pariſh of S. Dunſtans in the Eaſt, where he lyeth vnder a very faire monument erected, In his time was purchaſed by the Citty, certain houſes in Cornhill, amounting to the ſum of 532. poundes, or thereabout, and deliucred to ſir Thomas Greſham, whoe builded the ſame at his owne charge, &amp; on the 7. of Iune laid with his owne hands, the firſt ſtone.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Iohn Riuers.</item>
                     <item>Iames Hawes.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:11"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:11"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 9. Chriſto. Draper <hi>Ironmonger.</hi> 1566</p>
            <p>IN this yeare 1566. was ſir Chriſtopher Draper by common cuſtome choſen &amp; appointed Lord Mayor of this citty, the which place hee diſcharged with grea<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> grauity, and liued many yeares a Worſhipfull knight and Iuſtice in this cyttye, I finde nothing as yet of his almeſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>deedes, but as they come to hand, they ſhal be inſerted. This yeare there died within the compaſſe of ten monethes ſeuen ſeueral Aldermen, which hath not beene ſeene before or ſince that time. On mydſom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer euen at night this yeare, was the like ſtanding watch, as had bin on ſaint Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters euen the yeare before paſt. This Knight hath no monument erected, but lieth buried in a vanlt at ſaint Dunſtons in the Eaſt, without any further remembrance of any thing.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Rich. Lambert died</item>
                     <item>Ambroſe Nycholas</item>
                     <item>Iohn Langley.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:12"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:12"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 10. Sir Roger Martin <hi>Mercer.</hi> 1567</p>
            <p>SIr Roger Martin was now Lord Mayor of this citty, who diſcharged the ſame very grauely and as the place required, His bringing vp was not very great, but by his diſcreet carriage and good dealing, became in time a great mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chant in this citty and of great wealth, He was very courteous, and of a very ple<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſant and ieaſting ſpirit, He was ſo well taken amongſt men, that hee was choſen an Alderman firſt, after called to be ſheriffe of London, and in his due place may<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>or, this knight married a Grecian dame, and lyeth buried in the pariſh church of ſaint Antolines, vnder a very faire monument erected, This yeare there happened ſuch ſcarſitie of fodder and hay, that in diuers places the ſame was ſold by wail<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> for fiue pence the ſtone. No further can as yet be ſet downe of this knight.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Thomas Ramſey.</item>
                     <item>William Bond.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:13"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:13"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 11. Sir Tho. Rowe <hi>Merchantaylor.</hi> 1568</p>
            <p>THis yeare ſir Thomas Row was Lord Mayor, He did many works of charity amongſt which he compaſſed nigh one acre of ground neere Bedlem with a bricke wall, to bury the dead of all ſuch pariſhes as had not conuenient bu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riall, He alſo erected a gallary at Paules Croſſe, for gentlewomen to ſtande in to heare the ſermons, At his deceaſe he gaue vnto the Merchantaylors a hundred li<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> in money for the vſe of eight poore men, vſing clothworking or making of gar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments to vſe for two yeares for euer, He alſo gaue lands for the vſe of ten poore &amp; impotent men paſt labour, free of the Clothworkers, carpenters, tylers, playſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rers and Armorers, that is foure pound a man for euer, He was buried at Hackney vnder a very faire monument in that church erected.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Iohn Oleph.</item>
                     <item>Robert Harding.</item>
                     <item>Iames Bacon.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:14"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:14"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 12. Sir Alex. Avenon <hi>Ironmonger.</hi> 1509</p>
            <p>IN this yeare of ſir Alexander Auenon knight, and at this time Lord Mayor of this citty of London, there was no accuſtomed feaſt kept at the Guildhall, by reaſon that the peſtilence had now againe caught hold in furious manner with in this citty, but he held the cuſtome of going to Weſtminſter by water, and there had his charge deliuered. The rebellion in the North this yeare was very tedious, and many forces were conueyed thither to ſuppreſſe and bring vnder the violent outrage of thoſe Rebels, being the Earles of Northumberland and Weſtmerland. Of this knight as yet no further mention can be made, concerning either his place or any almeſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>deedes towards the reliefe of the needy, becauſe no certaine notice is found thereof, He was buried at ſaint Peters in cheape, but no monument.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Henry Becher.</item>
                     <item>William Dane.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:15"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:15"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 13. Sir Row. Heyward <hi>Clothworker.</hi> 1570</p>
            <p>SIr Rowland Heyward was Lord Mayor for this yeare 1570. and liued after till the yeare 1590. the iuſt compaſſe of twenty yeares, and then was the ſecond time Lord Mayor, he liued ſome thirty yeares, Alderman, knight and Iuſtice, in this famous citty, and at the time of his death, the ancienteſt vpon that worthy bench. He was a man of a very graue, wiſe, and couragious ſtomach, as might be well obſerued of him in his laſt time of gouernment, He was well beloued of ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny good men and women. In his firſt yeare, her Maieſty, accompanied with her Nobles, came to ſir Thomas Greſſams, and at her returne named the Burſſe, and called it the royall Exchange, He died in great credit, the 5 of Decem. 93. appoin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting two worthy citizens his executors, they erected for him a faire monument.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Frances Barnham</item>
                     <item>William Box.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:16"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:16"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 14. Sir Wilam Allin <hi>Mercer.</hi> 157<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
            </p>
            <p>THis yeare ſir William Allin was called to this high place, by the whole con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent and cuſtome of this citty, He was a man of no greater birth then a Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tizen of this cytty, and borne without Byſhopſgate, He had ſo tender a fee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling of the many neceſsities of the poore, that he would buy wood from the carte and diſtribute it with his owne hands, Beſides he would walke often through the ſaid pariſh, and ſuch poore as ſtood in need he gaue reliefe vnto, and at his death gaue a weekly porcion of bread to the poore of the ſame pariſh vpon euery ſabba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oth day for euer, and was buried in the pariſh church wherein hee was chriſtened. This yeare the citizens trained three times a weeke, the number of 3000. and on May day muſtred before the Queenes Maieſty at Greenwich.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Henry Mylles.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Branch.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:17"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:17"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 15 Sir Lyonell Dvcket <hi>Mercer.</hi> 1572</p>
            <p>IN this yeare of onr Lord aboueſaid, the choiſe of the lorde mayor of this cittye, was appointed to the gouernment and charge of ſir Lyoneli Ducket, who ſo be haued himſelfe in this high place, that hee gained vnto himſelfe great credite all the reſt of his daies, It ſhould alſo appeare by circumſtance, that he had a de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſire to raiſe the needy poore, by leauing a taſt of his bounty behind him, beſtow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing largely vpon the poore of the pariſh of Buckland in Barkſhire, in which place he reſted him, and gaue a farewell to London, and in that towne and pariſh end<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed his daies, and there lies buried. Many bi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> matters happned in his yeare, but no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing concerning himſelfe or this citty, can I finde as yet of certainty, but if any true notes come to hand, they ſhall be ioyned hereunto.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Rychard Pype.</item>
                     <item>Nicholas Wodroffe.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:18"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:18"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 16. Sir Iohn Ryuers <hi>Grocer.</hi> 1573</p>
            <p>THis yeare ſir Iohn Ryvers being free of the company of the Grocers, follo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wed the auncient ſolemnity, went to Weſtminſter by water and receiued his charge, and held a ſolemne feaſt at the Guildhall, He diſcharged the truſt to him committed with great grauity, care and dilligence, and yet in this yeare there aroſe a dearth both in corne and other victuals without any iuſt cauſe to bee gathered, for wheate was ſold in London for three ſhillinges the buſhell, and yet before the Chriſtmas following it roſe vp to ſeuen ſhillings the buſhell, and then all manner of victuall was inhanſed to greater prices, nothing haue I yet more to ſay of this knight, neither that he was buried in London, This yeare by reaſon of a great and vnaccuſtomed tempeſt, the boy was drowned at Dowgate.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Iames Harvey</item>
                     <item>Thomas Pulliſon</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:19"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:19"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 17 Sir Iam. Hawes <hi>Clothworker.</hi> 1574</p>
            <p>SIr Iames Hawes was this yeare called vpon and was Lorde Mayor of this Ho<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>nourable Cytty of London. This Mayor kept no feaſt at the Guildhall, and yet there was great preparation made for the ſame feaſt, as in former yeares it had bin accuſtomed, but dined at his owne houſe, accompanied with the reſt of the Aldermen his brethren, and the companies dined in their ſeuerall Halles. Mi<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>chaelmaſſe tearme which was adiourned by proclamation, began at Weſtminſter the 6. of Nouember. This yeare wheat and other graine, fell from 7. ſhillings to 3. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>llinges, as in the yeare before. More of this knight I cannot ſet downe, hee was buried in Abchurch, but no monument erected. Alſo this yeare happened many ſtrange accidents, as may more at large be read in the Chronicles.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Thomas Blanke.</item>
                     <item>Antho. Gammage.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:20"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:20"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 18. Sir Amroſe Nycholas <hi>Salter.</hi> 1575</p>
            <p>SIr Ambroſe Nycholas was by common conſent, called in this yeare of our Lord to the rule and gouernment of this citty, who effected the ſame in great grauity and circumſpect diligence, He kept no feaſt likewiſe at the guildhall but kept the cuſtome in going to Weſtminſter by water, and dined at his owne houſe, as for the companies they dined in their ſeuerall halles. This knight did many waies relieue and comfort the poore, and liued ſome few yeares a worthy knight and Iuſtice of the citty, and lies buried vnder a very faire monument at S. Mildreds church in Bredſtreet, nothing further canne be ſhewed concerning this knight as yet, This yeare Captaine Frobiſher ſet forth his firſt voyage to Cathay for gold, and brought one of the people of that countrey home with him.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Edward Osborne</item>
                     <item>Wolſtan Dyxy</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:21"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:21"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 19 Sir Iohn Landley <hi>goldsmith.</hi> 157<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
            </p>
            <p>IN this yeare ſir Iohn Landley came to the gouernment of this citty, and diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charged the truſt to him committed with great care and dilligence. In his year the Tower of London bridge was taken downe a new foundation being drawn sir Iohn being Mayor did take vpon him the laying of the firſt ſtone of this foun<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>dation vpon the 28 of Auguſt, in the preſence of both the ſheriffes, and t'woe of the maiſters of the Bridgehouſe, At his death he ſhould haue bin buried at ſaint Laurences, but in breaking vp the vault, one Ile of the church was in great d<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger of falling, and therefore was buried in the mayors chappell neare Guildhall. This yeare happened the ſudden damp<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> at the Syſes held at Oxford, whereof ſo many worthy Iuſtices and other people died ſuddenly.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>William Kempton.</item>
                     <item>George Barne.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:22"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:22"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 20 Sir Tho. Ramſey <hi>Grocer.</hi> 1577</p>
            <p>THis ſir Thomas Ramſey Lorde Mayor for this yeare with the godly dame Mary his wife, gaue the feeſimple of the yearly value of 243. pounds vnto Chriſtes Hoſpitall in London, to Peterhouſe in Cambridge yearelye 40. li. to 4 ſchollers, and two fellowes there. More x. li yearely to the poore of S. Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tholomewes, and ten pound yearely to poore priſoners, this to be continued for euer, the remainder to the poore children of Chriſts hoſpitall, theſe gitfs are much augmented by the good Lady. He continually relieued the poore. He gaue much towards the helping forward of young men retaylors of his company, hee was a very careful maieſtrate, &amp; walked in the feare of God, was well beloued, He liued 79. yeares, he lies in Saint Mary Wolnoth in Lumbard ſtreet.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Nicholas Backhouſe.</item>
                     <item>Fraunces Bowyer.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:23"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:23"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 21. Sir Richard Pype <hi>Draper.</hi> 1578</p>
            <p>THis yeare ſir Richard Pype being free of the worſhipful company of the Dra<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>pers, had the ſword and gouernment of this citty committed to his charge, in his yeare, about the xxii. of Ianuary, about ſeuen a clocke at night, the Nobility of this land, and this Mayor with his brethren the Aldermen, receyued Iohn Casſimere landing at the Tower wharffe, and with torchlight brought him to the houſe of ſir Thomas Greſham in Byſhopſgateſtreet. Alſo the new tower vpon London bridge whereon the heads of traytors ſtand, the foundation being layed the yeare before, was fully finiſhed in the moneth of Auguſt. Other accidents fel forth this yeare, but nothing touching the mayor, as yet I find, neyther that he was buryed in London,</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>George Bond.</item>
                     <item>Thomas Starkey.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:24"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:24"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 22 Sir Nych. wodroffe <hi>Habrdaſher</hi> 1579</p>
            <p>IN this yeare of our Lord, ſir Nycholas Wodroffe vſing the auncient cuſtome, tooke his charge at Weſtminſter, and his feaſt in the Guildhall, hee diſcharged the truſt to him committed, with great care and dilligence, and liued ſom few yeares after a Iuſtice of this citty, I finde no notes of his bounty as yet, but if any happen to hand hereafter, they ſhall be added, neither where he died or was bu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried, I cannot ſet downe. This yeare happened the great Earth quake, both here in London, and alſo generally throughout all England, except ſome part of the North, by which great hurt happened about London, it continued in London but a moment, but in ſome places it was felt three ſeuerall times, Many ſtrange acci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dents happened this yeare, as may be found at large in the Chronicles.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Martin Calthorpe.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Hart.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:25"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:25"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 23. Sir Iohn Branch <hi>Draper.</hi> 1580</p>
            <p>SIr Iohn Branch was called this yeare to bee Lord Mayor, and liued after hee had diſcharged this office ſome yeares. At his departure out of this life, he ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed by his Will many goodly Legacies, giftes, and remembrances to be done, amongſt all which he remembred the poore of the pariſh wherein he was an inhabitant, and gaue vnto the ſaid poore a ſumme of money, to be diſtributed at the diſcretion of the churchwardens and other the gouernors of that pariſh, alſo he lies buried in Abchurch, vnder a very faire monument erected by his Lady, and other of his kindred. This yeare came into England many of the Peeres of France, accompanied with a great traine, &amp; then was made ready the banquetting houſe alſo the Nobles of this land made great triumph before her Maieſty.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Ralph Woodcocke.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Allat.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:26"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:26"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 24. Sir Iames Harvey <hi>Ironmonger.</hi> 1581</p>
            <p>THis yeare of our Lord God ſir Iames Haruey was according to auncient ſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lemnity elected and choſen Lord Mayor of this Citty, and paſſed thorough this charge like a wiſe, graue, and diſcreet maieſtrate, hee liued ſome after yeares, but inſomuch as he hath a monument erected in the pariſh church of ſaint Dyoniſe in Fanchurchſtreat, and not yet finiſhed through the default of ſome who were put in truſt to finiſh the ſaid monument, I cannot ſet downe ſuch apt notes as might haue there haue bin found, This yeare Mounfieur the French kings bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, came into England, and was honourably receiued, both of the Nobles of the land, and this Lord Mayor, and the reſt of the Aldermen his brethren. And after ſome few moneths returned out of this land in great honor.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Richard Martyn.</item>
                     <item>William Webbe.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:27"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:27"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 25 Sir Tho. blanke <hi>Haberdaſher</hi> 1582</p>
            <p>IN this yeare ſir Thomas Blanke was Lord Mayor of this Honourable Citty, this mayor was borne and brought vp in this Citty, and vſed the trade of merchan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dize, he was accounted very religious in obſeruing Gods word, he was alſo ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>counted very iuſt and vpright in all his dealings, and a great maintainer of hoſpi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tality, to the poore he was a father and great comforter, hee was ſo well beloued and eſteemed amongſt both rich and poore, inſomuch that he was called by this name (The Good Knight) he liued the age of 74. yeares, and died the 28. of Oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tober 1588. and lyeth vnder a very faire monument at ſaint Mary Hill. In his year the Tearme was remoued to the Caſtle of Hertford. Alſo the ſtandart at Leaden Hall for thames water was in his time erected.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>William Roe.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Haydon.</item>
                     <item>Cuthbert Buckle.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:28"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:28"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 25. Sir Edw. Osborne <hi>Clothworker.</hi> 1583</p>
            <p>THis yeare of our Lorde ſir Edwarde Osborne was elected Lorde Mayor of this Citty, what countrey man he was, or of what parentage I find not, but as an apprentiſe he ſerned ſir William Huet before remembred, vſing mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chandize into France, Spaine, the ſtraights, &amp; other where, and after the ende of his ſeruice, married his ſaid maiſters daughter (hauing no other child) whereby his ſtate was greatly raiſed, This knight erected an euerlaſting monument in remem<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>brance of his ſaid mayſter, and father in Law, but none hath ſo requited his kind<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſe, for he lies buried in ſaint Dyoniſe church in Fanchurch ſtreet, but hath no mo<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>nument, nor further remembrance, as yet can be found, except in his company<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> I may hereafter come to more perfect remembrances.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>William Marſham.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Spencer.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:29"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:29"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 27 Sir Tho. Pulliſon <hi>Draper.</hi> 1584</p>
            <p>IN this yeare ſir Thomas Pulliſon ſerued this place of Honour, and diſcharged the ſame wich graue and diſcreet maieſtracy, the ſame knight yet liueth, but vp<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>on occaſions gaue vp, and liueth priuate. In his yeare her Maieſty (after her pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>greſſe) returned to her houſe at ſaint Iames, where the Citizens of London, to the number of 200. on horſſe, in veluet cotes and chaines of gold, and a thouſand on foot, with euery man a torch to giue light, they receiued her ioyfully, and on the 24. day of the ſame moneth, her Maieſty with her Nobles rode to the parlament houſe. Alſo this yeare the Citizens by commandement, muſtered to the number of 4000. at Mile <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>end and elſe-where, and on the x. of May skirmiſhed before her Maieſty at Greenwich, who gaue them great thanks.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Steven Slany.</item>
                     <item>Henry Byllingſly.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:30"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:30"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 28 Sir Wolſtan Dyxy <hi>Skynner.</hi> 1585</p>
            <p>SIr Wolſtan Dyxy being this yeare Lord Mayor, ſhewed himſelfe a worthy &amp; vpright maieſtrate, and as he bare himſelfe in his life and authority, ſo when God tooke him from the world, he left many remembrances of his charitable and godly deedes. As firſt, he gaue a porcion of land to his company to theyr vſe for euer, Alſo for certaine Diuine Lectvres to be read in a place appointed he hath giuen a yearly annuity. More he gaue bountifully to the poore of his pariſh, apoin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting a yearely ſumme to be diſtributed amongſt them, by the hands of the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany of the Skinners. This yeare was the ſecond Lottery for Armour, alſo the 14 Traytors were executed. This knight hath as yet no monument erected, but is bu<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ried in ſaint Mychaels at Baſhingſhaw.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Anthony Ratcliffe.</item>
                     <item>Henry Prannell.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:31"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:31"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 29 Sir George Barne <hi>Haberdaſher</hi> 1586</p>
            <p>SIr George Barne was this yeare Lord Mayor, and liued after the diſcharge of that place a gentle knight and well reputed Iuſtice of this fayre citty, the day of his entring, Ludgate being new finiſhed was opened, for the Councell to paſſe thorough to the Guildhall to dinner. This knight was the firſt aduenturer to Barbary, Rouſhia and Genua, he was alwaies accounted a great furtherer of a common wealth, hated couetouſneſſe, was glad to heare that young men proſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red, he alwaies ſet forward the poore mans cauſe. This mayor with his brethren in ſcarlet, and diuers Nobles of the land, with the number of 80. graue Citizens in veluet cotes and chaines of golde, with ſounde of trumpet made declaration of ſentence againſt the Queene of Scots, he was buried at ſ. Bartho. at the Exchange.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Robert Houſe.</item>
                     <item>William Elkin.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:32"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:32"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 30 Sir George Bond. 1587</p>
            <p>IN this yeare of our Lord this citties charge was giuen to this knight. Much tro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble was attempted againſt this land this yeare, All parts of the land was proui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded and put in readineſſe to make reſiſtance againſt the proud Spaniard, whoe came hither with full reſolution to captiuate this nation. Alſo her maieſty atten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded by her Nobility, paſſed forth to the campe lying at Tylbury, where ſhe in per<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſon viewed euery ſeuerall ranke, to the great ioy of all her ſubiects. Alſo after, it had pleaſed God to diſcomfite the enemy, this Lorde mayor and Aldermen with the Companies of this citty, aſſembled at Paules Croſſe, where was made a lear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned thankeſgiuing by M. Nowe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>, for the great deliuerye againſt the Spaniardes. This knight lies in the Mercers chappell, hauing no monument.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Thomas Skinner</item>
                     <item>Iohn Catcher</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:33"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:33"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 31 Sir Martin Calthorpe <hi>Draper.</hi> 1588</p>
            <p>THis yeare ſir Martin Calthorpe was Lord Mayor of this citty. In this yeare the xvii. of Nouember was appointed holliday, and the citizens were aſſem<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>bled at Paules croſſe. Alſo in this mayors time, her Maieſty attended by all the ſtates of this land, came in great royalty from ſomerſet houſe to paule<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>, and at temple barre, this Mayor and the reſt of the Aldermen receiued her maieſty, deli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uering vp al authority to her that gaue it, &amp; ſhe deliuered backe to this Mayor hir royall ſcepter, who bare the ſame before her, each ſeuerall company ſtanding on both ſides the way, from Fleetſtreat to paules, and returned backe by torchlight. After a little ſpace this mayor, aldermen, &amp; graue commoners receiued her again to weſtminſter, he died in his mayoralty, &amp; is buried at ſaint Mary Hill.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Hugh Ofley.</item>
                     <item>Rich. Saltingſtall.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:34"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:34"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 31 Sir Richard Martin <hi>Goldſmith.</hi> 1589</p>
            <p>SIr Richard Martin, (by occaſion of the death of ſir Martin Calthorpe) came at an vnaccuſtomed time of the yeare to this gouernment, namely the third day of May, in which moneth there was a generall fifteene gathered thoroughout London for the cleaſing of the Fleet ditch. Alſo this worthy knight being inuited to the Seargeants feaſt then held in the new Temple Hall (hauing certaine alder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men his brethren in company) at the Temple gate this Lord Mayor was by certen young Gentlemen of that houſe, denied entrance with his ſword borne vp before him, vpon which vncourteous demeanor made, hee returned backe to his owne houſe and did not dine with them. This knight liueth, hath bin twice Lord mayor he is a welbeloued Iuſtice, and the ancienteſt on that worthy bench.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Hugh Ofley.</item>
                     <item>Rich. Saltingſtall.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:35"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:35"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 32 Sir Iohn Hart <hi>groce.</hi> 1589</p>
            <p>THis yeare of our Lord, ſir Iohn Hart was Lord Mayor of this Honourable Citty. This yeare the Cittizens were often frighted with fire, firſt a great fire happened on Fiſhſtreet hill, burning the houſe downe to the ground, ſome two daies after, another houſe ouer againſt the firſt, againe, not paſſing 4 daies diſtant, another houſe and ſome people were burnt on the backeſide of the firſt houſe. Alſo this yeare were great tempeſt of winde. Alſo, in the moneth of September, there happened a great diſorder at Lincolnes Inne, betwixt prentiſes and the gentlemen of that houſe, ſo that ſome bloud was ſhed, and woulde haue growne more dangerous, had not the ſame by this wiſe maieſtrate bin appeaſed. He liueth a good knight, and an vpright and graue Iuſtice in this citty.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Richard Gurney.</item>
                     <item>Steuen Some.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:36"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:36"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 33. Sir Iohn Allat <hi>Fiſhmonger.</hi> 1590</p>
            <p>IN this yeare ſir Iohn Allat by conſent and cuſtome was Lorde Mayor of this citty, he was alſo Mayor of the Queenes ſtaple, he deceaſed in the moneth of ſeptember next following his entrance, and then ſir Rowland Heyward Cloth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>worker ſerued out that yeare, being about ſixe weekes. this yeare paſſed a verye hard yeare with the poore, for bread corne, fleſh, and whitmeates, al grew to an exceeding deare rate, and yet there was enough for money. Hacket this year was executed in Cheapeſide for many traitorous vſages of the Queenes picture, and being moued to aske God and the Queene forgiueneſſe, he fell to rauing againſt her maieſty, and began a moſt blaſphemous ſpeach againſt God, this knight lies <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>n a pariſh church in Fryday ſtreat hauing a pretty monument erected.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Nycholas Moſley.</item>
                     <item>Robert Brooke.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:37"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:37"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 34. Sir William Web <hi>Salter.</hi> 1591</p>
            <p>IN this yeare of our Lord ſir William Webbe keeping the vſuall ſolemnity and cuſtome went to Weſtminſter and receiued his charge, this knight diſcharged the place in great credit, and liued ſome few yeares a well accounted Iuſtice, at the place of his buriall, being ſaint Dunſtans in the Eaſt, I find no monument, but that he was buried in a vault, which is altogither reſerued for the better ſort, ney<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther as yet find any notes of his bounty. This yeare died ſir Chriſtopher Hatton Lord Chauncellor. Alſo this yeare by reaſon of a mighty ſtrong Weſt winde, the Thames was left ſo bare of water, by forcing out the freſh, and keeping back the ſalt water, that men in diuers places, might go two hundred paces ouer, and then fling a ſtone to the land.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>William Rider.</item>
                     <item>Bennet Barnham.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:38"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:38"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 35 Sir wiliam Roe <hi>Ironmonger.</hi> 1592</p>
            <p>THis Lord Mayor rode from the Guildhall to the Tower, and there tooke his Oath, being accompanied with the Aldermen, the Liuery and Batchelers of the Ironmongers, and the liuery of the Haberdaſhers and no more, all theſe dined at the Lord Mayors houſe, and at the halles of theſe two companies, all this was done by the appointment of the Councell, to auoyd infect<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> of the plague. Mychaelmaſſe tearme was carryed to Hertford. Alſo Bartholomew faire was not kept at London, all to auoyd the great concourſe of people that might haue byn gathered together, whereby the infection would haue increaſed. This Mayor dy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in his Mayoralty, ſome 3. or 4. daies before the ende of his honour, and lyeth buryed at ſaint Laurences, but hath no monument erected.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Iohn Garrard.</item>
                     <item>Robert Taylor.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:39"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:39"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 36 Sir Cuthbert Buckle <hi>Vintner.</hi> 1593</p>
            <p>SIr Cuthbert Buckle had his oath giuen him at the tower, as the Maior the year before him, becauſe the plague increaſed very extreamly, he himſelfe decea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed in the moneth of Iuly, and ſir Richard Martin was now the ſecond time L. Mayor, In this yeare died William Ellin Alderman, and a <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> benefactor vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to this citty, there died alſo ſir Rowland Heyward, and ſir Wolſtan Dyxye. Alſo the whole number of people buried this yeare in the citty and ſuburbes 17893. Of the plague 10675. After in this yeare the Cittizens made ready ſix ſhippes &amp; two Gallies, with men, munition, and victuals for three moneths to her Maieſties vſe. More was granted to her Maieſties vſe, by a common councell 450. men on foot all likewiſe ſet out at the charges of the cittizens by way of a fifteene.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Paul B<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>ning.</item>
                     <item>Peter Hautyn.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:40"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:40"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 37 Sir Iohn Spencer <hi>Clothworker.</hi> 1<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>94</p>
            <p>IN this yeare of our Lord, ſir Iohn Spencer was choſen Lord Mayor of this Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nourable citty, he receiued his honour and charge at We<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>tminſter, and his feaſt at the Guildhall. In this yeare as M. Iohn Stow recordeth, corner of to an ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſiue great price, and not only corne, but all manner victuals, by reaſon of tranſ<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>portation. Alſo this yeare diuers were puniſhed for abuſing the market people, in ſelling away th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> goods at what vnder price they thought good, More this yeare was a great ryot committed on the Tower hill, this Lord Mayor rode thithe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>companied with his officers to cleere the hill, where his ſwordbearer was ſtriken down, ſore wounded, &amp; his ſwo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>d wrung out of his hand by the lieutenants man, but being again recouered, this Lord Mayor made proclamation of peace.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Iohn Lee.</item>
                     <item>Thomas Bennet.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:41"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:41"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 38 Sir ſtephen Slany <hi>skinner.</hi> 159<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
            </p>
            <p>SIr Stephen Slany had this yeare committed to his charge. At this time it was thought neceſſary for two marſhals to be appointed for the purging and clen<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſing this citty from vagarent perſons. Alſo this yeare the Lord Mayor and al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dermen were fetched from the ſermon at Paules Croſſe, and forthwith vpon pre<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>cept from the Councell preſſed a thouſand men, which was done by 8. a clock the ſame night, but the next day by the afternoone they were all diſcharged, then ſud<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>denly on Eaſter day, euery man in his pariſh church being ready to receiue the co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munion, the Aldermen with their officers ſhut the church doores, till they had ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thered againe the 1000. men, which were going to Douer to ayde Callice, but the French had loſt it. This knight liueth a worthy iuſtice of this citty.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Thomas Lowe.</item>
                     <item>Leonard Halliday.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:42"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:42"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 39. Sir Tho. Skinner Clothwor. 1596</p>
            <p>THis ſir Thomas Skinner being choſen Mayor for this yeare, and ſeeing the great diſtreſſe of breadcorne to grow ſo vnmercifull deare, that the faces of the poore did manifeſt their want, this Mayor in a feeling compaſſion, pitty and care, prouided that breadcorne ſhoulde bee brought from Danske, and other the Eaſt countries by our Merchants, who had freely giuen them both cuſtome &amp; ſtowage, and alſo to make their owne price, ſo that his great care brought with it this good, that corne was to be had for money. In this yeare was great triumphe for the preſeruation of her Maieſty. He liued but a while in his honor, and died the 30 of Decem. and lies buried in Milkeſtreat. He was of a ſtout ſtomach, very mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cifull and vpright and whoſe death was much bewayled of the poore.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Richard Goddard.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Wats.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:43"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:43"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 39 Sir Henry Bilignſly <hi>Haberda.</hi> 1596</p>
            <p>SIr Henry Billingſly by reaſon of the death of the other Mayor, was elected &amp; choſen to ſerue the reſt of the yeare in this place of honor, whoe beeing chiefe Cuſtomer for her Maieſty, vpon twelfe ce<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>e ſat in the cuſtome houſe with the ſword lying before him on the table, and on the xi. of Ianuary he tooke his Oath at the Tower of London, this happened by reaſon that ſir Thomas Skinner liued but about ſome two moneths in that office. The great dearth was not yet abated, for the ſpring fell out very cold, and alſo great prouiſion was made to ſea, where by victuals kept a very high price, yet in the moneth of Auguſt, the prices of grain ſomthing abated, wheat from xiii. <abbr>s.</abbr> to x. and Rye from 9. to 6. &amp; ſo to 3. <abbr>s</abbr> 2 <abbr>d.</abbr> but it after roſe againe. He liueth a Iuſtice and chiefe cuſtomer to her Maieſty.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Richard Goddard.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Wats.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:44"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:44"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 40 Sir Rich. Saltonſton <hi>skinner.</hi> 1597</p>
            <p>IN this yeare of our Lord, this Lord Mayor was by common conſent &amp; cuſtom elected, and ſerued this place to him committed in great quiet and peace, In this yeare began the reading of Lectures of the ſeuerall ſciences in ſir Thomas Greſhams colledge by him founded in Biſhopſgateſtreat. Alſo this yeare began the Parliament at Weſtminſter in October, wheras through the mighty recourſe of people, diuers were cruſhed and ſmouldred to death, preaſing betwixt White hall and the colledge church, to ſee her maieſty and Nobility riding in their robes to the ſaid parliament, ſir thomas Garrard and his men making way before them Alſo this yeare was great froſts, this knight is lately deceaſed, ſo that as yet I haue not gathered true notes togither.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Henry Roe.</item>
                     <item>Iohn More.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:45"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:45"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 41. Sir ſtephen Some <hi>Grocer.</hi> 1598</p>
            <p>THis yeare the gouernment of this citty was committed to this knight, In his time he rouſed vp a great corruption long before lying hidde, to the great dammage of people, (namely falſe waightes and meaſures, vſed in buying &amp; ſelling) wherby great good may inſue to this citty, if the eie of Iuſtice take ſom view thereof now and then. Alſo in his time was rayſed a great muſter of men in this citty of 6000. of which, three thouſand wer houſholders only, the other three thouſand all ſubſidy men picked forth of euery ward, to guard the Queenes per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, all which companies muſtred at Mileend in gallant manner (this Mayor him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelfe comming into the field, giuing great thankes to the cittizens for their great forwardneſſe. He liueth a worthy Iuſtice, and a man of couragious ſtomach.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Edmond Holmdon.</item>
                     <item>Robert Hampſon.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:46"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:46"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 42 Sir Nych. Moſly <hi>Clothworker</hi> 1599</p>
            <p>SIr Nycholas Moſley was for this yeare Lord Mayor of London, whoſe paſſage in his gouernment is freſh in the memory of euery man, This knight ſo beha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ued himſelfe in this place of honour, and vſed ſuch care and conſcience there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withall, as well might pleaſe the beſt minded, His care was great and very dilli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gent in ſeeing into the markets, that they might not exact vpon the buyers, Alſo he had euer a ſpeciall eye to Bakers, to hold them to their aſſiſes, wherby the poor man might haue his penniworth, Againe towards Victualers, by reaſon that they are growne many and bad, whoſe meaſure is in generall without all conſcience. Alſo great abuſe in ſeacoles, he to his power did cauſe to be amended, ſetting the cittyes armes vpon euery cart that ought to carry true meaſure too and fro.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Rychard Wylde.</item>
                     <item>Roger Clarke.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="biography">
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:47"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:47"/>
            <figure/>
            <p>
               <hi>An. reg.</hi> 43. Sir Wil Ryder <hi>Haberdaſher.</hi> 1600</p>
            <p>THis preſent yeare of our Lord, the gouernment of this Citty by the ful con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent and auncient cuſtome of our Cittizens, was committed to ſir Willyam Ryder, now Lord Mayor of this Honourable cittye of London. Of whoſe worthineſſe in his place euery eie may witneſſe, whoſe care in maintenance of the good of this citty, ſheweth it ſelfe dayly by his great paines taking, in reformati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of an olde and long corruption rooted amongeſt men, in abuſing the true vſe of waight and meaſure, and that his cares herein may bee the better remembred, he hath ordained in euery market place, common ſcales and waights, wherein all men may find out fraud and deceit with the author thereof, Alſo his dilligent eye for his princes ſeruice hath bin quicke &amp; worthy the truſt to him committed.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sheriffes.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>Thomas Cambell.</item>
                     <item>William Craven.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:48"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:9584:48"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
